Guide to the American Service Institute Records, ca. 1920-1961 AIS.1963.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Individual and Family Case Files, IV.
  - Individuals' Open Case Files, 2.
    - Scott, Edmunde and Takako (Box 21, Folder 69)
    - Scriva, Paul (Box 21, Folder 70)
    - Seka, Charles (Box 21, Folder 71)
    - Simecek, Milada (Box 21, Folder 72)
    - Simeone, John (Box 21, Folder 73)
    - Simms, Stephen (Box 21, Folder 74)
    - Simon, Louis (Box 21, Folder 75)
    - Simonis (Box 21, Folder 76)
    - Smalinskes, Walter (Stavinsky) (Box 21, Folder 77)
    - Smith, Henry (Box 21, Folder 78)
    - Soehl, Mrs. Emmi (Box 21, Folder 79)
    - Spekis (Box 21, Folder 80)
    - Spirich, George (Spirovska) (Box 21, Folder 81)
    - Stanson, Louis J. (Box 21, Folder 82)
    - Stefanovich, Lazar (Box 21, Folder 83)
    - Stefanyak, Joseph (Box 21, Folder 84)
    - Stojanoff, Welitchko (Box 21, Folder 85)
    - Stokke, Mr. Nils and Mrs. Sigrid (Box 21, Folder 86)
    - Svenungsen, Mrs. Louise (Box 21, Folder 87)
    - Tannous, Amin (Box 21, Folder 88)
    - Tenz, Manfred K. (Box 21, Folder 89)
    - Theodore, Anthony John (Box 21, Folder 90)
    - Toila, Mr. Evald (Box 21, Folder 91)
    - Tomedolsky, Charles (Box 21, Folder 92)
    - Tonkovich, Frank (Box 21, Folder 93)
    - Toropoff, Vladmir (Box 21, Folder 94)
    - Tratras, George (Box 21, Folder 95)
    - Trenga (Box 21, Folder 96)
    - Vassilve, Marko (Box 21, Folder 97)
    - Velicoff, Steve (Box 21, Folder 98)
    - Velizarov, Bogdan, Petrov (Box 21, Folder 99)
    - Veris, Spiros (Box 21, Folder 100)
    - Winters, Mrs. Catherine A. (Box 21, Folder 101)
    - Wisnilwski, Stanislau (Stanley) (Box 21, Folder 102)
    - Wychowanek, Tadeusz (Box 21, Folder 103)
    - Yagodkin, Constantine (Box 21, Folder 104)
    - Young, Robert E. (Box 21, Folder 105)
    - Zack, Edward and Eva (Box 21, Folder 106)
    - Zafiris, Mary (Marika) (Box 21, Folder 107)
    - Zemaitis (Box 21, Folder 108)
    - Zervos, Nicholas M. and Mary (Box 21, Folder 109)
    - Ziatek, Wlodzimiierz (Box 21, Folder 110)
    - Znavor, Steve (Box 21, Folder 111)
  - Service Requests, 3.
    - Inquiries Re Questionnaire for Citizenship (Box 22, Folder 1-2)
    - Incidental Service (by month), 1941 (Box 22, Folder 3-14)
    - Records cancelled - Social Service Exchange (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Intake (by month), January 1941 - February 1942 (Box 22, Folder 16-27)
    - Intake (Brief Service) (by year), 1942-1951 (Box 22, Folder 28-38)
    - Brief Service Cases, 1952 (Box 22, Folder 39)
    - Service to Agencies and Organizations, 1951 (Box 22, Folder 40)
  - McKeesport Records, 4.
    - Documents from McKeesport files (Box 22, Folder 41)
    - Documents from McKeesport files (Box 22, Folder 42)
    - Caliguri (Box 22, Folder 43)
    - Piacentino - Maietta (Box 22, Folder 44)
    - Simon (Box 22, Folder 45)
    - Rlaszka (Box 22, Folder 46)
    - Tabaoff (Box 22, Folder 47)
    - Juhasz (Box 22, Folder 48)
    - Phillips (Box 22, Folder 49)
    - Veliff (Box 22, Folder 50)
    - Lejia (Orndowska-Drapinska) (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Pittsburgh Records, 5.
    - Documents (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Roman-Rominez (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Castelli (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Galanes (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Gallicchio (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Hallack (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Hospodar (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Karasi (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Kail (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Lessik (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Seligman (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Urban (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Grominski (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Koukoutsis (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Peluco (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Wendt (Newakowski) (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous other cases (Box 23, Folder 18-19)
    - Reg, 1939 (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - Hadar (Box 23, Folder 21)
- Employment Progress Reports, V.
  Series V contains files called 'process record' used to monitor the performance of new staff and student interns. These files contain information about projects and staff which demonstrate some of the internal functions of ASI.
  - Process Record on Allegheny Valley - Miss Ruth Smalley, 1947-1948 (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - Process Record Case Work Committee - Kermit Wiltse, 1949-1950 (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - Process Record Case Work Committee - I.B. Lindsay (Committee on Cultural Factors in Case Work), 1948-1949 (Box 23, Folder 24-25)
  - Student Record Allegheny Valley - AMS, 1948-1949 (Box 23, Folder 26)
  - Process Record Upper Allegheny Valley - Arthur Stevenson, 1948-1949 (Box 23, Folder 27)
  - Process Record McKeesport Intercultural Council - Boris Clarke, 1949 (Box 23, Folder 28)
  - Process Record McKeesport - Boris Clarke, 1948-1950 (Box 23, Folder 29-30)
  - Process Record McKeesport - Joseph Ring, 1950-1951 (Box 23, Folder 31)
  - Process Record Hazelwood Project - D. Forney, 1944-1945 (Box 23, Folder 32-33)
  - Process Record Allegheny Valley Advisory committee Citizen Recognition Ceremonies, 1949 (Box 23, Folder 34)
  - Process Record Group Work Committee - I.B. Lindsay, 1948-1949 (Box 23, Folder 35)
  - Process Record Edgar Flood Committee (PittSSW) Cultural Factors Special Project Committee, 1954-1955 (Box 23, Folder 36-37)
  - Process Record - Peggy Holmes, 1950-1951 (Box 23, Folder 38)
  - Process Record Fraternal Society of Pittsburgh and ASI - Kamel ElBatrik, 1951-1952 (Box 23, Folder 39-40)
  - Process Record PTA Committee - Edgar Floods, 1954-1955 (Box 23, Folder 41-43)
  - Process Record PCIE Public Relations Committee "Penn Township Profile" - Robert Mast, 1956-1957 (Box 23, Folder 44-45)
  - Process Record Teacher Coop. Committee (PCIE) Publicity Committee - Yehuda Rosenman, 1945-1946 (Box 23, Folder 46)
  - Process Record PCIE: Books Committee, PTA Committee - James Hackshaw 1948-1949 (Box 24, Folder 1-2)
  - Process Record Intercultural Youth Council (IYC) - J.J. Horowitz 1950-1951 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Process Record Books Committee (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Process Record IYS - L. Fehr, H. McDermott 1951-1952 (Box 24, Folder 5-7)
  - Process Record Youth Section - Elizabeth Lamborn 1949-1950 copy #1 (Box 24, Folder 8-9)
  - Process Record Youth Section - Elizabeth Lamborn 1949-1950 copy #2 (Box 24, Folder 10-12)
  - Process Record Youth advisory Committee 1950-1951 J.J. Horwitz (Box 24, Folder 13-14)
  - Process Record youth Section Filomena Florendo 1949 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Process record War Relief Agencies Luncheons, Malvin Morton 1944-1945 (Box 24, Folder 16-17)
- Newsletters and Publications, VI.
  Series VI contains ASI newsletters listed by community, including some of the research used to produce the publication.
  - ASI Newsletters (some with research), 1.
    - News Letter Volumes 1-9 (Box 24, Folder 18-26)
    - News Letter 1952-1960 (Box 24, Folder 27)
    - Nationality Fact Sheets (Box 24, Folder 28)
    - News Letters Duplicates (Box 24, Folder 29)
  - Newsletters by Community, 2.
    - Allegheny County (Box 24, Folder 30)
    - Bloomfield (Box 24, Folder 31)
    - Braddock (Box 24, Folder 32)
    - Charleroi (Box 24, Folder 33)
    - Coraopolis (Box 24, Folder 34)
    - Duquesne (Box 24, Folder 35)
    - Hill District (Box 24, Folder 36)
    - Homewood-Brushton (Box 24, Folder 37)
    - Lawrenceville (Box 24, Folder 38)
    - McKeesport (Box 24, Folder 39)
    - McKeesport research (Box 24, Folder 40)
    - McKees Rocks (Box 24, Folder 41)
    - Monongahela (Box 24, Folder 42)
    - Mt. Lebanon (Box 24, Folder 43)
    - New Castle (Box 24, Folder 44)
    - Oakland (Box 24, Folder 45)
    - Pittsburgh (Box 24, Folder 46)
    - Penn Township (Box 24, Folder 47)
    - South Side (Box 24, Folder 48)
    - Squirrel Hill (Box 24, Folder 49)
    - Tarentum (Box 24, Folder 50)
    - West Deer Township (Box 24, Folder 51)
    - Wilkinsburg (Box 24, Folder 52)
    - Community Cooperation (Box 24, Folder 53)
    - General Community Research (Box 24, Folder 54)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 24, Folder 55)
    - Resources for community leaders (Box 24, Folder 56)
    - Community Tensions (Box 24, Folder 57)
- Additional ASI Files, VII.
  Series VII consists of ASI cultural information and administrative files. The files contain a small amount of information about local cultures and traditions, research notes, examples and correspondence about ASI publications, and ASI agendas, minutes, and reports from 1955-1961. There are also some black and white photgraphs which show ASI employees and groups of people who attended ASI's citizenship classes.
  - Miscellaneous Material on Ethnic Groups (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - The Study, Diagnosis, Treatment Sequence as an Aid to Initiating Community Organization Service, April, 1956 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Pennsylvania, Historical items about Pennsylvania programs (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - National Conference of Social Work, Reservations (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Folk Festivals (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Foods (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Culture (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Cultural Factors, Social Work (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Fraternal Societies Mailing Lists, old, 1952 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Foreign Born in America (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Second Generation Americans (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Allegheny County's Americans By Choice, booklet, lists, correspondence, 1944 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - ASI Professional Staff's Concerns, Social Work, The Foreign Born, Their Families, Summer, 1959 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - ASI Employment Directory for New Americans with correspondence, January, 1960 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Survey Beneficial Fraternal Societies, October, 1957 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - ASI Newsletter, Requests, correspondence, publicity, lists, 1941-1959 (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - ASI Intercultural Digest, Lists, correspondence, etc., 1944-1949 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - ASI Service Directory for New Americans, Lists, correspondence, 1st Edition, June, 1953 (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Do You Know Your Neighbor?, article, correspondence, February, 1947 (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Articles Written By Staff, correspondence, publications, up to 1950 (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - ASI Miscellaneous Agendas, Minutes, Reports, etc., 1955-1961 (Box 25, Folder 21-22)
  - ASI Photographs, Unidentified, ca. 1940-1950 (Box 25, Folder 23)
- Map and Statistics Binders, VIII.
  Series VIII includes four ring binders that contain maps, transparency overlays, statistics sheets, typed and handwritten cultural information sheets, and newsletter and newspaper excerpts. The maps show population breakdowns in Pittsburgh neighborhoods arranged by nationality, income, age, and race. The clippings from newsletters and newspapers, typed commentary, and statistics explain the maps in greater detail and discuss how to integrate immigrants into American society. There is also information about community councils, neighborhood profiles, and local education, housing, health, religion and crime rates. All of this information centers on data from the 1940s and 1950s, and most is culled from the census. Texts of studies, reports, and presentations from both outside sources and the ASI, as well as copies of ASI press releases and letters, complement the maps and statistics.
  - City Population Groups, ASI Purpose and Programs (Box 25, Volume 1)
  - Age Distribution, Immigration, Topography, Community Councils, Neighborhoods Profiles (Box 25, Volume 2)
  - Social Factors, Blight, Education, Crime (Box 25, Volume 3)
  - Housing, Health, Religion (Box 25, Volume 4)